Muhammad Zeeshan Akram

Nishtar Colony, Ferozpur Road, Lahore, Pakistan 54600; Mobile: **+92 3053761717**; Email: **19100254@lums.edu.pk**; Github: **github.com/MZeeshanAkram**

SUMMARY

A full-stack Web Developer proficient in MERN stack having over 1 of experience. Developed a numbers of small web-apps and interactive front-end components. Well-versed in asynchronous workflow and functional programming in JavaScript. Strong knowledge in JavaScript frameworks such as React.js for client side, Node.js/Express for server side and MongoDB for database. Apart from Web Development, avid learner of Statistics and interested in Machine Learning. Well-versed in python frameworks for machine learning and Implemented a number of deep learning models.

EDUCATION

Lahore University of Management Sciences(LUMS)

August 2015 - May 2019

BS (Computer Science)

Relevant Courses: Software Engineering, Network Security, Algorithms, Entrepreneurship, Statistics, Deep Learning, Advanced Programming

EXPERIENCE

Incline-Al

Robotics Intern - Autonomous Car

December 2018 - January 2019

- Developed User Interface to stream camera data of Self-driving car using react and flask-restful api.
- Worked on improving Robot localization and Object detection algorithms using **ROS framework** in python.

LUMS

Research Fellow - CS

August 2018 - December 2018

- In semester-long search project, Collected and Analyzed data pertinent to ads served on Alexa top 500 Global sites; studied different characteristics of ads such as language, area served, target audience, etc.
- Examined the impact of different Circumvention mechanisms on the online advertising system. Devised a mechanism to serve geographically relevant ads to users in **Tor Browser** without undermining their anonymity.

PROJECTS

- MERN Stack App: Developed a web platform Volunteer Finder for NGO's to help them find appropriate volunteers for their nonprofit events using MERN Stack framework. (top 5% of class)
- Oracle SQL Project: Used schema of the U.S. Patent database to answer complex queries about patents, their inventors, parent companies and citations using Oracle SQL
- Text Generation using RNN: Build a RNN in python; generated the example texts given the input file. Also classified a collection of Facebook statuses into abusive and non-abusive using LSTMs.
- Parallel Execution in Golang: Used U.S. Census Bureau data to answer real world questions, for swift data manipulation Golang was used as preferred language as it provided framework for effective parallelism; the project was 75% time efficient than sequential python script.
- Emulating impact of EVs on Grid Load: Devised an optimal night scheduling solution for electric vehicle charging by analyzing LESCO last six months of Grid Load data, available at the granularity of 15 mins; devised different Machine Learning and Regression techniques in **R** to better forecast energy usage; the model predicted household electricity usage with 97% accuracy.
- NachOS Project: Implemented the key components of modern operating systems (thread management, multiprogramming, and file systems) in NachOS on a MIPS emulator.
- Developed Open edX Site: Studied Open edX framework and its components such as LMS, Studio and XBlock plugins; developed a simple site and configured its theme.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE

- · Languages: Node.is, GoLang, Python, SQL, MongoDB, Pytorch, Tensorflow, Redux, Haskell
- Frameworks and Tools: Jira, Google Cloud, JWS, Panda, Rest-full APIs, Express.js

HONOURS AND AWARDS

- . 2 Million Rupees NOP scholarship (10% acceptance rate) from LUMS (2015-19)
- Fully funded Higher secondary school education from KIPS college. (2013-15).